Esta lição 23 de PEMSLO Inglês 1.
Listen to this conversation. How many children
do you have, Mr. Martins? 2. My wife and
I have 2 children, a girl and a boy. Are they here
in America with you? Yes, they are, and tomorrow we're going
to Long Island. Listen again.
How many children do you have, Mr. Martins?
Two. My wife and I have two children, a girl and
a boy. Are they here in America with you? Yes, they are.
And tomorrow we're going to Long Island.
Say in English, car.
Car. Nosso carro.
Our car.
Say nossa família.
Our family.
Ask quantas
pessoas há?
How many people are there?
Na sua família.
In your family.
Ask quantas pessoas há na sua família?
How many people are there in your family?
Answer: Cinco pessoas.
Five people.
Há cinco pessoas na nossa família.
There are five people in our family.
Nós temos três filhos.
We have three children.
Usando o número, diga um menino e duas meninas.
One boy and two girls.
Try to say, "As meninas estão aqui na América." The
girls are here in America.
The girls are here in America.
Conosco. With us.
Nosso menino pequeno está no Brasil.
Our little boy is in Brazil.
Ask verdade?
Really?
Say, nós temos uma família grande.
We have a big family.
A big family.
Now try to say, nós não temos uma
família grande.
We don't have a big family.
Há três pessoas na nossa família.
There are
three people in our family.
Nós temos uma família pequena. Listen and repeat.
We have a small family.
Small. Small.
Small, assim como little, quer dizer pequeno,
mas se usam em vários contextos. Com família e carro,
frequentemente se usa a palavra small. Diga outra vez
que vocês têm uma família pequena.
We have a small family.
Try to say,
and we
have a small car.
A small car.
Ask where the bathroom is.
Where's the bathroom?
How do you say? Como se diz? How do you say?
Fica lá.
It's over there.
In English, how do you say? Como se diz em inglês?
Gasolina. Gas.
Gas. Ask, quanto custa?
How much is it?
Answer, custa dois dólares por galão.
It's two dollars per gallon.
Per gallon. It's two dollars
per gallon.
Say, enche o tanque, por favor.
Fill it up, please.
Ask, você pode esperar?
Can you wait?
Say, meu carro é grande demais.
My car is too big.
Eu quero um carro pequeno.
I want a small car.
A small car.
Eu quero um carro menor. Listen and repeat.
I want a smaller car.
Smaller.
A smaller car.
Say, eu quero um carro menor.
I want a smaller car.
Você se lembra de como se diz mais caro?
More expensive.
Para fazer uma comparação em inglês com palavras longas, tais como
expensive, se usa more. More expensive.
Com palavras curtas, tais como small, se deve adicionar
o som er ao final da palavra. Smaller. Diga-me outra
vez que você quer um carro menor.
I want a smaller car.
A smaller car.
Now ask, Você tem gasolina suficiente?
Do you have enough gas?
Enough gas.
Usando o número, tente dizer: a gasolina custa um dólar
por galão.
Gas is one dollar per gallon.
Então enche o tanque, por favor.
Then fill it up, please.
Agora pergunte ao homem onde ele vai.
Where are you going?
Say, eu vou para Long Island.
I'm going to Long Island.
Say, eu vou para Long Island amanhã.
I'm going to Long Island tomorrow.
Ask, ¿cuántas millas?
How many miles?
Miles. How many miles?
Ask how many miles it is to Long Island.
How many miles is it to Long Island?
How many miles is it?
Fica longe. Listen and repeat. It's far.
Far. Far.
It's far. How do
you say? Como se diz fica longe?
It's far.
Ask if Long Island is far.
Is Long Island far?
Setenta milhas. Tente adivinhar como se diz o número setenta.
70. 70.
How do you say setenta milhas?
70 miles.
Say não, setenta e um.
No, seventy-one.
Say. Espere.
Wait. Say.
Você fala rápido demais.
You speak too fast.
Fica longe. It's far.
Long Island fica longe.
Long Island is far.
It's far.
Ask, você tem gasolina suficiente?
Do you have enough gas?
Responda brevemente que sim.
Yes, I do. Say that
you have a small car.
I have a small car.
Now try to say, eu quero um carro maior.
I want a bigger car.
Bigger. A bigger car.
Eu quero um carro mais caro.
I want a more expensive car.
A more expensive car.
Now say again. Eu quero um carro maior.
I want a bigger car.
Agora você quer perguntar: é esta estrada para Long Island?
Primeiro a palavra estrada. Listen and repeat.
Road. Road.
The road. Say again.
A estrada. The road.
Try to say a estrada para Long Island.
The road to Long Island.
Agora esta estrada. Listen and repeat.
This road.
This.
This. This road.
Esta estrada para Long Island. Listen and repeat again.
Is this the road to Long Island?
The road. The road
to Long Island.
This. Is this?
Is this the road to Long Island?
Ask again. É esta estrada para Long Island?
Say. Eu não sei.
I don't know. Mas Long
Island fica longe.
But Long Island is far.
Ask, quantas milhas são?
How many miles is it?
Try to say, setenta e cinco milhas.
Seventy-five miles.
It's seventy-five miles.
Ask again. É esta estrada para Long Island?
Is this the road to Long Island?
Não, a estrada para Long Island.
No, the road to Long Island.
Fica adiante. Listen and repeat. Is straight
ahead.
Ahead.
Straight.
Straight. Straight ahead. Say,
agiante.
Straight ahead. The road
to Long Island is straight ahead.
Now say,
Espere. Wait. Essa não é a
estrada para Long Island. Listen and repeat.
That's not the road to Long Island.
That's not.
That is not.
That's not the road to Long Island.
Say again. Essa não é a estrada para Long Island.
A estrada para Long Island?
The road to Long Island.
Fica lá. Is over
there.
Ask: Adiante?
Straight ahead?
Straight ahead? Say: Sim,
adiante.
Yes, straight ahead.
Ask her how much gas she wants. Ask her how much gas
How much gas do you want?
Ask how much it is.
How much is it?
Custa dois dólares por galão.
It's two dollars per gallon.
Say, "Não." Espere.
No, wait.
Aqui custa um dólar por galão. Use o número.
Here it's one dollar per gallon.
Então enche o tanque, por favor.
Then fill it up, please.
Say muito obrigada.
Thank you very much.
Como você responde?
You're welcome.
Ask: Long Island fica longe?
Is Long Island far?
Answer: Não, não fica longe.
No, it's not far.
Long Island isn't far.
Ask, quantas milhas?
How many miles?
How many miles is it?
Try to say, setenta e oito milhas.
Seventy-eight miles.
It's 78 miles.
It's 78 miles to Long Island.
Pergunte se esta estrada para Long Island.
Is this the road to Long Island?
Try to say, "Não, esta não é a estrada para
Long Island." No,
this isn't the road to Long Island.
Isn't. This isn't
the road to Long Island.
Pergunte outra vez se esta é a estrada para Long Island.
Is this the road to Long Island?
Answer: Não, esta não é a estrada para Long Island.
No, this isn't the road to Long Island.
Answer: A estrada para Long Island.
The road to Long Island.
Fica adiante.
Is straight ahead.
The road to Long Island is straight ahead.
Ask. Você tem gasolina suficiente?
Do you have enough gas?
Diga que você tem muita gasolina.
I have a lot of gas.
A lot of gas.
Diga que você tem um carro pequeno.
I have a small car.
Eu gostaria de um carro maior.
I'd like a bigger car.
Bigger. A bigger car.
Sei, mas Long Island não fica longe.
But Long Island isn't far.
Como você discordaria brevemente?
Yes, it is.
Yes, Long Island is far.
Agora, suponha que você está dirigindo para Long Island com sua
família. Você para num posto de gasolina. Responda à pergunta do empregado
dizendo-lhe que você gostaria que ele enchesse o tanque. Good morning,
ma'am. How much gas do you want?
Fill it up, please.
Agora pergunte-lhe se esta é a estrada para Long Island.
Is this the road to Long Island?
Yes, it is. Long Island is straight ahead.
Pergunte quantas milhas são daqui a Long Island.
Daqui se subentende.
How many miles is it to Long Island?
It's not too far, sixty or seventy
miles. Agradeça-lhe.
Thank you. Thank you
very much.
Agora ele nota os filhos no carro e diz: Você
tem uma família grande. Diga-o.
You have a big family.
Say, sim, há sete pessoas na nossa família.
Yes, there are seven people in our family.
Agora, despeça-se dele.
Goodbye. Nesta lição de inglês um se incluem exercícios de leitura.